<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Story Ideas</title>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html</link>
<description>deitarion/SSokolow's fanfiction idea bin and plot plan collection.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 ssokolow</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 01:07:12 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 01:07:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
<generator>TiddlyWiki 2.6.5</generator>
<item>
<title>Well, I Didn't Vote For You!</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; How about a story where first-contact war leaves a humanity with a propensity to spin off disgruntled break-away states and terrorist groups (of a different character than Cerberus).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After reading the fics mentioned under &quot;Inspiration&quot; it occurred to me that, given human nature, the discovery of the prothean ruins on Mars resulting in a unified Earth government is a bit of a case of &quot;Bioware wrote it this way because author says so&quot;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As humans, we're a fractious bunch and, even in this day and age, we still sometimes see new countries being fissioned off. It would make perfect sense if, by the time Mass Effect rolls around, humanity is either still on the United Nations model of global politics or has an uneasy world government which would shatter like glass when some parts of humanity declare that the world leaders did not have the authority and, thus, the citadel council's political standing is invalid.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That would then produce a cauldron of unrest which would periodically produce attempts at breakaway republics and terrorist groups defined not by their decision to practice asymmetric warfare the way Cerberus does (the breakaway republics would also be doing that) but by their actual use of terror tactics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, I'd need to think about some way to make the breakaway republics more interesting than just an ongoing sparkle of &quot;rebellion... pacified&quot; around human space. (I'd want to research unconventional &quot;nations&quot; and see how all kinds of nations could be applied to a space contect.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;...how exactly does the whole &quot;need to discharge the drive core&quot; part work? Is there any way a breakaway state could, at thought-to-be-prohibitive expense, develop some kind of solution for getting outside the normal selection of worlds? (eg. Would it be possible to build a &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matryoshka_doll&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matryoshka_doll&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matryoshka&lt;/a&gt; ship where the built-up charge is discarded along with each shell+engines layer? What about some kind of normally-prohibitive method of capturing the charge and then discarding the capture vessel/material?)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Maybe I could bluff the readers with a line analogous to &quot;With no Relay, it will make a direct jump to the Citadel, but will need significant work done on its engines before it will fly again.&quot; from &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10454482/19/Early-Discovery&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10454482/19/Early-Discovery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Early Discovery, Chapter 19&lt;/a&gt; where, because I just take it for granted that it's possible, the &quot;destructively long survivable jump&quot; comes across as &quot;the author knows what he's doing, but explaining it would dilute the story as a whole&quot;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Either way, it'd be primarily about the politics rather than the tech anyway so I don't want to let thinking about that side-track me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; Read the Wikipedia article on &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asymmetric_warfare&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asymmetric_warfare&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;asymmetric warfare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; If done believably, it's also possible that an advantage could be had as a result of surviving a &quot;suicidal gambit&quot; and making a technological breakthrough as a result of it. (&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10454482/10/Early-Discovery&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10454482/10/Early-Discovery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;inspiration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/7104229/1/The-Day-the-Arms-Closed&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/7104229/1/The-Day-the-Arms-Closed&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Day The Arms Closed&lt;/a&gt; is probably the closest I've yet seen, but focuses itself very differently from my vision.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt; Reading fics like &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10636239/1/A-Dark-Dawn&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10636239/1/A-Dark-Dawn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Dark Dawn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/9527774/1/The-Illusive-Emperor&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/9527774/1/The-Illusive-Emperor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Illusive Emperor&lt;/a&gt; </description>
<category>Mass Effect</category>
<category>IdeaFragment</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BWell%2C%20I%20Didn't%20Vote%20For%20You!%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 01:07:10 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>X-COM</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Ideas based on the &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;X-COM&quot;&gt;X-COM&lt;/a&gt; games.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Differences between the original and rebooted &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;X-COM&quot;&gt;X-COM&lt;/a&gt; series:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Obviously, the original series has 1990s-level plot development.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; In the new series, the aliens are holding back more, so &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;X-COM&quot;&gt;X-COM&lt;/a&gt;'s plight doesn't come across as nearly as desperate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The insanely harsh RNG in the original series prompted the fans to impute an &quot;ends justify any means&quot; character to humanity's plight and &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;X-COM&quot;&gt;X-COM&lt;/a&gt;'s character.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<category>SourceSeries</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 22:31:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>ME-Com</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The Ethereals from &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#X-COM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;X-COM&quot;&gt;X-COM&lt;/a&gt; are actually Protheans who survived the last cycle.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Think about it:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; The Ethereals are running from something and the reapers fit quite well.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Prothean society was a multi-species empire with the original Prothean species at the top. Now compare to the Ethereals.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; 50,000 years is easily enough for Protheans to engineer their reading abilities into powerful psi abilities. (Hell, their beacons already have the appearance of telepathy in Mass Effect canon, regardless of how they actually work.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Any divergent technology can be explained as intentional R&amp;amp;D to escape the reaper technology trap.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<category>Mass Effect</category>
<category>In A Different Light</category>
<category>X-COM</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#ME-Com</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 22:29:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Cursed! Whodunnit?</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; One day, without warning, Hinako turns male. Shortly afterwards, Hiroshi and Daisuke reveal that they've been cursed for several months already but they kept it a secret. The game is afoot and the question on everybody's mind is &quot;How did Ranma's curse become contagious, why now, and why THEM? After all, Akane spends plenty of time around Ranma and nobody has started turning into a panda.&quot; Cursed! Whodunnit?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Cursed! Whodunnit? - Attempt&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Cursed! Whodunnit? - Attempt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Cursed! Whodunnit? - Attempt&quot;&gt;Experimental Attempt at Writing It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Story Structure:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Main Story: A Whodunnit-style story beginning with Hinako getting &quot;spontaneously cursed&quot; and ending, at the earliest, once they know what's going on. (Though that'll probably just be the main subplot. Seeing how Yuka and Sayuri deal with the curse and react to Hiro and Dai's curses could be good fun too.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Prequel to be read afterwards: A view of how Hiroshi and Daisuke reacted to getting cursed, how they kept it secret, their motivations for doing so, and what they did with their curses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Subplots for the main story:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; The whodunnit&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hinako (In cursed form, 'he' is stable at an in-between age. This gives the clarity necessary to see the extremes she bounces between. With that, she can figure out what she's done for her students, both good and bad, and so on. The conflict is that she wants to go back to normal but she doesn't want to lose that clarity.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Yuka and Sayuri (&quot;Cliche&quot; pretty much doesn't exist when dealing with female-to-male transformation and, if we decide that they're currently dating or considering dating Hiroshi and Daisuke, then we REALLY have some fun options. Probably best to make a clean break from male-to-female cliche by having the guys be the experienced once. Additional fun can be had if, once they're used to being guys, Yuka and Sayuri decide to take the intiative and not only date Hiro and Dai, but suggest things Hiro and Dai either never considered or decided against intially... but not girl training. That brings back the cliche.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Herb (Lime and Mint end up cursed before this story even starts because of how much Herb blasts them. However, Herb doesn't know why until he receives a letter from Ranma detailing the events of this story up to a certain point. However, while dragon heritage provides for ki production and control, damping isn't so easy. This results in a character crisis (he's almost certain to eventually curse his bride) until Ranma comes up with a solution. However, he has to put his pride on the line to let Ranma teach him. Lime and Mint get cured... by force (Hinako) if need be.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Subplots not needed:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Kasumi seems unaffected by getting cursed and serenely trusts that Ranma will find a cure. This really gets on Akane's nerves... especially since some of Kasumi's mannerisms really don't fit with a male body. (As a plus, periodic cut-aways to Kasumi can entertainingly build on the underlying theme.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Nabiki is pretty imperturbable. She'll just end up deciding to keep the curse so that she can become a male business tycoon if need be. After all, by this time, it'll be obvious that only Ranma has the water magnetism.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Kuno may get cursed &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rules:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Ranma's curse taints his ki. Prolonged exposure to Ranma's curse causes peoples' ki to slowly become curse-tainted. Enough taint and you start changing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The osmotic taint only works for gender-curses because other curses are &quot;too much work&quot; to implement. (Complete genetic rewrite for most, Large mass change for age curses, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Male-to-female curses are much easier than female-to-male curses because no Y chromosome needs to be synthesized.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Also, Hiroshi and Daisuke have been hanging around Ranma long before Hinako showed up.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Cursed people are immune. (Genma, Shampoo, Taro, Mousse, Ryoga)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Happosai's ability to drain and convert female ki has taught him to filter what he draws but he knows what's going on and he finds it hilarious. He doesn't tell anyone because he's a jerk that way.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hinako is the most vulnerable female because of her draining ability and how frequently she uses it on Ranma.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Her &quot;Happo no Yen Coin Return&quot; doesn't purge her ki system because her techniques make a distinction between native and foreign ki. Because it would probably bring her back to her original weakened state, she never flares her native ki.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Draining Ranma's ki is similar to glomping onto him for several hours while having weakened defenses. That's why she picks up a curse much more quickly than Yuka and Sayuri.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Cologne has never heard of this because it's really the first time population density, ki mastery, huge ki reserves, and a gender curse have combined in this fashion.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; The amazons know that a gender-cursed mother will give birth to gender-cursed children, but not why. Other kinds of curses don't spread this way because 9 months isn't enough exposure.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Herb probably hasn't heard of this either, given how the Musk feel about gender-segregation.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; It doesn't help that neither the Amazons nor the Musk have an equivalent to &quot;sit three feet away from a cursed ki adept for six to eight hours, six days a week&quot;. (school)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The curses won't make Hiroshi and Daisuke into water magnets. Maybe it only works for Ki adepts who fight their curses. (The old &quot;chi in turmoil&quot; explanation)&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Note: The explanation doesn't really matter as long as Hiro, Dai, Yuka, Sayuri, and our choice of anyone who inherits a gender curse are free of water magnetism.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Akane isn't the first girl to get cursed because flaring your aura (in her case, getting angry) helps to flush the taint out.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Kasumi is the second girl to get cursed after Hinako. (Not only does Ranma live there, Kasumi does his laundry. If Happosai can get charged by panties, then Kasumi can get tainted by laundry)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Yuka and Sayuri are the third and fourth girls to get cursed. No boys other than Hiro and Dai have been cursed yet. (Ranma keeps his aura controlled and they're the only non-immune (Akane) people other than Hiro and Dai who spend that much time in range)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Ranma will learn to control his ki to prevent further tainting by the end of the story and will teach Herb and probably Cologne too so it can be recorded for future generations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hinako can cure someone by draining them twice in rapid succession. However, the taint regenerates once you're cursed, so accidental curing by non-consecutive drains is impossible. Two drains will render a person unconscious for 12 to 24 hours but do no permanent damage. The body won't allow fatal amounts of ki to be drained. Cologne explains this so they'll allow it to be done.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Nabiki gets cursed fifth: After Kasumi is changed, Ranma starts to think that the change has something to do with him. When Akane's friends are affected as well, he's completely confused. In a concerted attempt to find out what's going on, he and Nabiki, who's helping him because she's worried for Kasumi, spend days sifting through books on Jusenkyo at the Cat Cafe and Dr. Tofu's. During this time, Ranma's using his aura to keep himself awake, and heavily exposing Nabiki. When Nabiki is changed, Ranma finally realizes, at least basically, what's going on.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;deitarion&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In essence, if you're a martial artist, you're unlikely to get cursed via osmosis. If you're cursed (doesn't matter how) you only spread it via osmosis if you're a strong martial artist.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the main themes of the ending, IMHO, are what happens when Ranma finds out the mechanics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; he knows he'll lose control of his aura occasionally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; what will he do about it?&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Then again, with Nabiki and at least one of the couples HAPPY about it, that may not matter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Questions to be Answered:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do Hiroshi and Daisuke's parents already know about their curses before Hinako spontaneously gains one?&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It's entirely possible that the families know, but the boys have convinced them not to tell for several reasons.&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; The families don't know that Hiro and Dai are harmless letchers,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Well, let's face it, having a son that turns into a girl is rather embarassing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ...though revealing it in the main story could be amusing, too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Do we want to curse Gosunkugi in order to set up for a &quot;Gos + Girl = Goth = People taking interest &lt;code&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; Why!?&quot; joke?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Ideas:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Maybe Daisuke can borrow one of his mother's old wigs for his female form until his hair grows out. (Either the wig will match his natural color or &quot;she&quot; will claim she had the hairstylist dye her hair back to its natural color when his real hair looks apropriately androgynous)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &quot;How did you keep this a secret for so long?&quot; &quot;I dunno. We just don't seem to attract water the way you do... or trouble for that matter.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; By the time Yuka and Sayuri reach saturation point, they'll be so resigned to the probability of it that when one of them transforms in school, 'he' will jokingly turn to some of the other girls and respond with &quot;Ok... does anyone have a pickle jar they need help with?&quot;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Notes:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hiroshi's hairstyle looks half credible as a girl's cut but Daisuke would need to grow his bangs down in the side not to look really odd as a girl. A hairstyle change could play a part in the plot. (&quot;And here I thought Dai only started growin' that ponytail ta copy me or somethin.&quot; or something equivalent)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Subplot timelines need to be written. Possibly using HTML tables to get parallel columns, one per subplot.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hiroshi and Daisuke's curses aren't going to kick in at the same time (too implausible) so, In the prequel, it's a given that the phrase &quot;Can I touch them?&quot; will get used at least once. A good response would probably be something along the lines of &quot;Not now. I haven't even had a chance yet.&quot; but with more effort made to make it funny.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;weebee&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  Hmm, now that I think of it, this isn't a disease. It's radiation exposure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;deitarion&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Heh heh heh. That's great. &quot;The Virus&quot; turns the curse into a disease. I'm turning it into radiation poisoning. :P&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:28:53) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; First, a simple thought that, once the news of the extra curses has spread enough for the  administration to not take issue with it, I'd like Hiro and Dai to come  to school in female form in borrowed uniforms at the request of some of  the girls. It'd be an opportunity to flesh out characters all around.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:31:11) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; ...but especially the female characters. Of all the bits in the Ranma anime that I enjoyed, the one that felt the most unique and memorable was probably Ukyo having fun playing with Ranma's curse. (The part that, in the dub, ended with &quot;I'm not a plaything!&quot;)&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:32:18) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; always preferred &quot;I'm not a toy,&quot; but that dub was mostly okay, so meh.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:32:45) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; I prefer that too, but it's been too long and audio stick in my mind better than subtitles.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:32:52) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; sticks*&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:32:55) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; Same reason I enjoyed Boku no Futatsu no Tsubasa. Anime and manga have a frustrating tendency to mute the fact that girls are human beings too.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:32:57) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; Hiroshi and Daisuke are taking this pretty  well all around, so it could be all right. Though having someone should almost certainly flip out over it a bit more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:33:28) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; Remember, the plot summary says &quot;Shortly afterwards, Hiroshi and Daisuke reveal that they've been cursed for several months already but they kept it a secret.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:33:42) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; agreed,&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:33:46) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; they still took it pretty well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:33:53) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; being capable of keeping it secret, especially.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:34:49) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; I've always had a fondness for the idea that there be some way to appease the rule of funny so the water magnet effect goes away.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:35:48) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; well, it doesnt even need to be rule of funny, that's not what I meant.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:35:57) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; though I suppose their parents might have found out and not told.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:36:07) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; the initial flipout would at least give it away to them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:36:32) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; anyhow, it's easy to explain no water magnetism, or much less. Curse is weaker since it's a 'secondary infection,' and the gender change itself is more important.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:37:42) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; That'd actually work well since the parents could help provide the cash for the latter part of &quot;Daisuke or Hiroshi: A little time alone with some cold water clears up a  lot of mysteries. Getting leered at and hit on while out to buy some  girl clothes... more than I wanted.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:38:11) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; yeah, presumably.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:38:21) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; This IS Furinkan-cho. It's somewhat canon that people are desensitized to crazy things happening.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:38:44) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; make this a &quot;Meh&quot; nerima similar to Help Wanted's, and the parents could even just be like &quot;I told you hanging out with that Ranma boy woul dbe trouble...&quot; or something.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:39:16) weebee:&lt;/strong&gt; whole bunch of ways to take it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12:39:24) deitarion:&lt;/strong&gt; *snicker* Yup.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Reference:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://furinkan.com/ranma/characters/daisuke.html&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://furinkan.com/ranma/characters/daisuke.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Daisuke &amp;amp; Hiroshi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://furinkan.com/ranma/characters/yuka.html&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://furinkan.com/ranma/characters/yuka.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yuka &amp;amp; Sayuri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Note to Self: If I ever need the chatlogs with weebee, I believe everything was discussed in one fairly long chat on 2009-03-28.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Timeline: (Under Development)&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Ranma begins Ki training around the time of the Amaguriken. Ranma's aura, tainted with the Jusenkyo curse, begins radiating into his near surroundings. This effect will continue to strengthen as his training continues.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hinako arrives and begins draining Ranma's aura.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Herb arrives, battles Ranma, and then returns to China.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Lime and Mint reach taint saturation, having absorbed it quickly from constant exposure and frequently being on the receiving end of Ki blasts. They manifest curses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hiroshi and Daisuke reach saturation point (when? Volume 36?) but decide to keep it a secret.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; There should be a day or two between them since it's more or less impossible that they'd get equal exposure.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Main story starts here.&lt;/strong&gt; Hinako reaches saturation point a few weeks after the end of the manga. (Volume 38) Hiroshi and Daisuke reveal their own curses at this point.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;/strong&gt;Somewhere in here, Yuka, Sayuri, and Kasumi reach saturation point. Ranma starts to get seriously concerned.&lt;strong&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Nabiki gets involved, helping Ranma search for a cure for Kasumi's sake.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Ranma sends a letter to Herb asking if he knows of anything like this.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Nabiki reaches saturation point within three days of working with Ranma. Ranma realizes the basic mechanics of the process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Ranma, Nabiki, and Cologne begin to try and determine the specifics.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; A few days to a few weeks pass, depending on the needs of subplots.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Herb Arrives with Lime and Mint.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;How much time passes in here?&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Ranma and Cologne figure out the cure to the problem, Ranma devises a method to supress his own aura totally, based on Dr. Tofu's old technique and the Umisenken, and he teaches it to Herb. Kasumi gets cured.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; End of story?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<category>StoryPlan</category>
<category>ChatLog</category>
<category>Favored</category>
<category>Gender-Bending</category>
<category>Under-Explored Characters</category>
<category>Ranma ½</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BCursed!%20Whodunnit%3F%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 21:38:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Cursed! Whodunnit? - Attempt</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;See Also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Cursed! Whodunnit?&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Cursed! Whodunnit?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Cursed! Whodunnit?&quot;&gt;Cursed! Whodunnit?&lt;/a&gt; (story plan)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&quot;Another English class, another day of boredom,&quot; Ranma thought to himself. Everything was ordinary. Students doing very little studying, Miss Hinako doing very little teaching, and Ranma with little to do but nap and toss the odd distraction in the general direction of their variably-aged teacher.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was at that moment that things decided to go from normal to abnormal and did so even more quickly than was normal for Nerima. Miss Hinako had been firmly focused on finding the best way to combine her strawberry milk with the lemon lolipop Ranma had given her five minutes ago when the elastic on one one of her shoes slipped and she took a tumble, sending her milk flying.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In an instant, two very strange things had happened. The cold liquid hadn't, as it always did, somehow ended up on Ranma Saotome but, instead, on Miss Hinako herself, who had gone from a young girl to a teenage boy in a tight, yellow dress in the blink of an eye. Ranma just blinked lazily for a second, a yawn almost coming to his lips, before that last observation rammed its way through his sleep- and boredom-fogged mind.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Wait... Miss Hinako had just turned into a man? He blinked slowly several times, the unreal image refusing to go away. The week's weirdness quota was now well and truly satisfied.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursed! Whodunnit?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By: deitarion/SSokolow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, for most schools, a teacher spontaneously changing gender in front of a class would be followed fairly quickly and abruptly by some combination of shocked silence, confusion, and panic... but, given their history with the insane, the bizarre, and the just plain stupid, the students of Furinkan High (and especially those of class 1-F) can be excused for having slightly higher standards. After a few furtive glances at each other, the thankfully principal-free windows and door, and their own secondary-sex characteristics (not necessarily in that order), normal operation resumed and the class, as one, began reacting.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marked&quot;&gt;TODO:&lt;/span&gt; Finish thinking on how Miss Hinako would react. Given how Genma didn't seem to even notice his curse at first, and how Ranma, once used to his curse, often doesn't even notice he's changed, and that Hinako is quite used to transformation of a different sort, I think it's quite plausible that it would take her a few moments to realize that she's no longer in a familiar form. (Likely as a result of a &quot;Do I have something on my face&quot;-esque thought in response to the class's behaviour)&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(19:28:49) jonakhensu:&lt;/strong&gt; also, the one problem I saw for Hinako not noticing she changed: panties not being at all comfortable on a guy- is lessened by the fact that she probably doesn't wear any&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(19:33:37) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; *nod* Doubt she'd be able to find something that sits equally well on her small and large forms and, as with one of the fanon tracks for Ranma's curse, I doubt she'll ever have a period unless she can stay in adult form for at least a month.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marked&quot;&gt;Potential fragment:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While this was going on, Akane had been busy weighing the evidence and, based on long experience, had reached the highly prescient (though still tentative) conclusion that this was all Ranma's fault, as usual.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marked&quot;&gt;Potential narrative response to a line of dialogue:&lt;/span&gt; suave to stupid in &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; seconds flat. (with the number being how long the dialogue would take to say.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Random Idea Fragment (100% Raw)&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;[Write: Hiroshi and Daisuke admit they've already been cursed for several months.]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;??? (probably female): &quot;So that's why you have been less pervy lately? I thought Akane finally scared you into toning it down.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hiroshi or Daisuke (Mock affronted tone, if it's not too &quot;Weasley Twins&quot;): We were sharing classes with Akane long before Ranma was keeping her busy. Why do you think she's the only person who calls Ranma a pervert?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Daisuke or Hiroshi: A little time alone with some cold water clears up a lot of mysteries. Getting leered at and hit on while out to buy some girl clothes... more than I wanted.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[Probably immediately followed with Ranma asking why the heck they'd want to buy girl clothes and Hiro/Dai responding with &quot;Not everyone wants to be the center of attention, 'pigtailed girl'.&quot; with that last bit in a teasing tone.]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Also, I think, once the news of the extra curses has spread enough for the administration to not take issue with it, I'd like Hiro and Dai to come to school in female form in borrowed uniforms at the request of some of the girls. It'd be an opportunity to flesh out characters all around.</description>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BCursed!%20Whodunnit%3F%20-%20Attempt%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 16:33:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Odds and Ends</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Unsorted bits and bobs... usually too short to have their own page.&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; How about writing my own &quot;Odd Ideas&quot;?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Try writing a report/log/journal-style story like The Virus.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Stuff too short for its own page:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &quot;Hulk Sell!&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:;&quot; title=&quot;show inspiration&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; closedtext=&quot;inspiration&quot; closedtip=&quot;show inspiration&quot; openedtext=&quot;inspiration&quot; openedtip=&quot;hide inspiration&quot; hover=&quot;false&quot;&gt;inspiration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;floatingPanel&quot; transient=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;display: none; left: 0px; top: 0px;&quot;&gt;"So, you're like a Hulk now?" She asked, putting her hand on Xander arm and feeling the muscle beneath. Wow, how much do you weigh now, or lift, oh my god, I bet you're stronger than Buffy now!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I don't know, Xander laughed as they walked out of the house into the night, ducking under the doorway as he did. They should have someone take a look at that, shoddy workmanship.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Yeah, Jennifer replied with a grin. We just knocked and it caved right in, no defence against door to door salesmen.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Somehow, I get the feeling that &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayanami_Rei&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayanami_Rei&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rei&lt;/a&gt; reading &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Faust&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Faust&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Faust&lt;/a&gt; would have interesting effects. (&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/5093352/1/Deus-ex-Evangelion&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/5093352/1/Deus-ex-Evangelion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;inspiration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Outsider comment regarding the crazy/fanatical Cylon Model Ones to use in an nBSG fic: *sigh* There's at least one in every family.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; How about a Futaba-kun Change fic that doesn't cross over with Ranma 1/2? (it would be a first)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; What other stories could be set in &quot;The Virus&quot;-verse? (eg. What series haven't been crossed in yet?)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The world can always use more good fanfics for under-appreciated series like El Hazard, Sabre Marionette J, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Send someone who isn't the main character back in time to the beginning of the series. (bonus points if they're not even a main character)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Look into possible ways for the concept of &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/1046500/1/I_Was_A_Teenage_Dummy_Plug&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/1046500/1/I_Was_A_Teenage_Dummy_Plug&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I Was A Teenage Dummy Plug&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to be applied to other source series.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; How about a &quot;self insert&quot; where the person admits to being godly but doesn't do anything godly because their preferred method of meddling is to use chaos theory to solve problems? (Preferring to use their omniscience rather than their omnipotence)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; How about a Beavis and Butthead gender-bend crackfic? (Inspired by something in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2160751/1/&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2160751/1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Uhhhhh ok&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Try to get some inspiration from the comment about Utena and OMG-style valkyries on &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.deviantart.com/deviation/45038318/&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.deviantart.com/deviation/45038318/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; If I can't find a decent implementation of the final author note from &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/3107822/18/&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/3107822/18/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Wild Horse Thesis&lt;/a&gt;, then I should write it myself.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Once I've finished figuring out how to model characters accurately and I've got a few stories under my belt, I should start completing the current story arcs on old Addventure favorites. Then I should try asking for permission to complete standalone fics, eventually working my way up to &quot;Forever The Tomboy&quot; and &quot;Girl Days&quot; once I hopefully have enough of a reputation to receive it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&quot;You're forgetting that this is the guy who drinks a glass of chocolate milk by drinking the glass and throwing away the milk, which then explodes. For him, BLT probably means something like Begonia, Lead, and Tarantula... and that's assuming he wants to hit all three food groups.&quot; (animal, vegetable, and mineral)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ponder these for ideas:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Discworld:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Dumbledore has seven portraits but only six are known... because the seventh is hidden in the Patrician's palace in Ankh-Morpork where the magic field is so strong that Dumbledore's portrait self can step out of the portrait into reality in case of emergency. &lt;span&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2512228/19/Harry_Potter_and_the_Color_of_Magic&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2512228/19/Harry_Potter_and_the_Color_of_Magic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Color of Magic, Chapter 19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Neon Genesis Evangelion:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Some of the AU universes touched on in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://tinyurl.com/gymgz&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://tinyurl.com/gymgz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://tinyurl.com/gymgz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://tinyurl.com/marzs&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://tinyurl.com/marzs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://tinyurl.com/marzs&lt;/a&gt; (Chapters 15 and 16 of Innortal's &quot;True Angel&quot;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Perhaps something starting at &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/170181.html&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/170181.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/170181.html&lt;/a&gt; and involving &quot;Dual!: Parallel Trouble Adventure&quot;?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Sailor Moon:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/203004.html&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/203004.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/203004.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Slayers:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/35529.html&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/35529.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://addventure.bast-enterprises.de/35529.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Idea bins open for public use:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Neon Genesis Evangelion:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/5092329/1/Spare_Parts&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/5092329/1/Spare_Parts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spare Parts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/5344173/1/The_Beginnings_Repository&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/5344173/1/The_Beginnings_Repository&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Beginnings Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Analysis TODO&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This category is for stuff that's probably only relevant to me at the moment but may become generally-useful ideas later on.&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Re-read &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/345621/1/Generation_Lost&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/345621/1/Generation_Lost&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Generation Lost&lt;/a&gt;&quot; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.florestica.com/jtemple/gl/index.htm&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.florestica.com/jtemple/gl/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;, identify what about it captivates me, distill it, and design a fic plan to reproduce it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Analyze &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2056653/1/Eldritch_Asylum&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2056653/1/Eldritch_Asylum&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eldritch Asylum&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to identify what about it I crave and what pitfalls to avoid... then look into writing something like that once I've proven that no more fics like that exist.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Figure out what atmosphere/tone traits appeal to me in the combination of Make a Wish &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2318355/38/Make_A_Wish&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2318355/38/Make_A_Wish&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chapter 38&lt;/a&gt; and luinlothana's omake on &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2318355/39/Make_A_Wish&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fanfiction.net/s/2318355/39/Make_A_Wish&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chapter 39&lt;/a&gt; and plan a fic around them. (In essence, a Harry Potter (-ish) fic that mixes in a modern North American setting without completely throwing out the baby with the bathwater)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<category>TODO</category>
<category>Discworld</category>
<category>Harry Potter</category>
<category>Neon Genesis Evangelion</category>
<category>Sailor Moon</category>
<category>Slayers</category>
<category>The Virus</category>
<category>Saber Marionette J</category>
<category>Futaba-kun Change</category>
<category>Oh! My Goddess</category>
<category>Full Metal Panic</category>
<category>ChatLog</category>
<category>Magical Girl Lyrical Nanoha</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<category>Ranma ½</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BOdds%20and%20Ends%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 05:34:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Self-Deception, Changeling-Style</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; When changelings encounter problems, our habit is to hide... even from ourselves, it seems. I couldn't bear to confront my past, so I tried to just leave it behind and let the guilt and remorse die with the name I'd forsaken and the face I shunned. ...it didn't work very well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/75755/3/molded-to-love/scars-of-the-past&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/75755/3/molded-to-love/scars-of-the-past&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/75755/3/molded-to-love/scars-of-the-past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; Brainstorm interpretations of that dialogue snippet.</description>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BSelf-Deception%2C%20Changeling-Style%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 04:47:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Not Your Ordinary Cutie Mark</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Stories have made some great justifications for the nature of cutie marks being cultural... what if exceptional circumstances could alter their position or nature in more exceptional ways?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Some stories have put a lot of thought into the nature of cutie marks. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For example, in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fimfiction.net/story/57315/13/the-xenophiles-guide-to-equestria/ponies-behaving-badly&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fimfiction.net/story/57315/13/the-xenophiles-guide-to-equestria/ponies-behaving-badly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Xenophile's Guide to Equestria, Chapter 13 (Ponies Behaving Badly&lt;/a&gt;, a deeply-considered and perfectly canon-reasonable argument is made for how much of the form cutie marks take is nurture, not nature. (ie. not only is the iconography based on what the subject is familiar with, but things like marks running may come and go as societies change.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Given that and how loosely defined the whole setting is, why not a story built around coming to terms with some kind of &quot;extremely exceptional circumstances produce something well outside the normal bounds of 'cutie mark'&quot; as the driving conflict?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt; Just a random thought when I was looking at a scene from the cartoon and thinking about how it makes sense to put an athletic contestant's number over their cutie mark because, with their cutie mark being probably the most distinctive single feature on their body, habit would probably draw the eyes there when trying to remember who someone is.</description>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>But... But... Potential!</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BNot%20Your%20Ordinary%20Cutie%20Mark%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 06:14:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>...More Like Queen Bee</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Psychologically, changelings are basically a fourth pony tribe with equivalent reproductive biology and queens like Chrysalis are a product of an ancient ritual. (But, depending on how the idea is fleshed out, the changelings may have forgotten that.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Instead of being natural or essential, changeling queens are a safeguard against extinction through population collapse crafted by changeling mages back in the mists of antiquity... sort of like Leeloo from The Fifth Element (a genetically-perfect being) implemented in a manner similar to the Slayer line in Buffy the Vampire Slayer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Point: Changelings Are Essentially Ponies&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; However the author decides to handle changelings feeding on emotions (essential nutrient, required to use their horns, or even just a power booster), there does exist at least one way in which they can feed non-destructively enough to sustainably join a society.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Changelings are in the same neurological ballpark as ponies, griffins, minotaurs, and other intelligent, civilized species and any barbarism present is cultural.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Queens are not an essential part of the changeling lifecycle, society, culture, or psychology... though they may have forgotten that.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; While it's up to the author whether changelings have any kind of telepathy, if they have a hive mind, it doesn't grant queens any special extra ability to subvert other changelings' wills above and beyond any mind-control spells they may already know.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Point: Changeling Queens Weren't Evolved&lt;/h2&gt;Long ago (Possibly Discord's reign but I think I'd prefer to set it in the pre-unification period), the changeling species saw itself in dire straits (whether through war, a wildly varying food supply, or something else).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In a desperate attempt to stave off their seemingly invevitable extinction, a group of the brightest changeling mages worked together to design and implement an enchantment on the entire species which would implement a genetic life raft: The Changeling Queen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Changeling queens are defined by several differences from regular changelings:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; There must always be at least one.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; If the only queen is killed, a changeling somewhere will begin to undergo what could be described as a second puberty.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The spell will prefer female changelings but, if the author doesn't build in a &quot;the last male changeling in the world would become a queen&quot; clause, they must believably argue that it wasn't for lack of trying on the mages' parts. (After all, there's always the possibility that the last males and the last females could get separated and then the females could die.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; It's up to the author whether more than one queen is possible. My intuition says that the best choice would be to have queens able to choose to have daughters who are also queens but that there's some downside to it, either biological or cultural.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; It could be as simple as &quot;Why should I have an heir? She's just going to try to depose me.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; It could be that queens have their magical enhancements from the start and, as such, run their parents/guardians even more ragged than usual.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; If the author decides changelings have a hive mind, maybe it's an integral part of how the spell was cast and how it detects and implements recovery from the loss of the last queen. (Which could also open up interesting avenues for plots based on a new queen being &quot;called&quot; because the old one was broken from the link, either temporarily or permanently, without being killed.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Their bodies are too resource intensive to be a feasible transformation to slowly apply to the full changeling population.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; They are as genetically perfect as the mages could make them so that they can repopulate an entire species without birth defects from inbreeding.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; It's up to the author whether parthenogenesis is possible but, given that they already feed on emotions, I'm rather partial to the idea of a queen being able to have as many one-night stands as she wants in order to build genetic diversity. Hey, if things like Griffins and Discord can exist, why not a spell which ensures maximum genetic compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Aside from increased rather than decreased fertility, they have been engineered to take a similar role to the role Pak Protectors play relative to species like Humans in Larry Niven's Known Space universe.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Their lifespan and memory are significantly enhanced so they can act as living repositories of knowledge until society is re-established.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Their magical and physical abilities are superior to other changeling to ensure maximum survivability of themselves and any dependent offspring.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Their bodies are engineered to support an alternative, insect-like reproductive cycle so that maximum population growth can be achieved by offloading as much of the gestation period as possible onto previous generations of offspring. (Think marsupials or seahorses who use a hive rather than a pouch.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;Of course, despite all this, the creators of this grand plan were operating under a time crunch and were merely mortal, they cut some corners and relied a little too much on optimism so who knows how much might have been forgotten about the nature and purpose of queens. For all we know, the author might decide that changelings think their queen is blessed by some deity with a divine right to rule.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt; Chrysalis's mental monologue on the ability of her children to breed and have children of their own without birth defects in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/134427/4/never-judge-a-bug-by-her-cover-chrysaliss-royal-break-up-chronicle/my-ass-is-damn-fine&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/134427/4/never-judge-a-bug-by-her-cover-chrysaliss-royal-break-up-chronicle/my-ass-is-damn-fine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Never Judge a Bug By Her Cover: Chrysalis's Royal Break-up Chronicle, Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>Vague</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5B...More%20Like%20Queen%20Bee%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 05:55:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Miss Effect</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; What about a story set in the future of the Mass Effect universe where the Reapers missed humanity because we fled?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:;&quot; title=&quot;show This quote&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; closedtext=&quot;This quote&quot; closedtip=&quot;show This quote&quot; openedtext=&quot;This quote&quot; openedtip=&quot;hide This quote&quot; hover=&quot;false&quot;&gt;This quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;floatingPanel&quot; transient=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;display: none; left: 0px; top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&quot;Suddenly we were confronted with the realization that we were going to be facing the apocalypse. It practically drove us mad. Most of our leaders had no idea what to do, others used it as an excuse to hoard more power. This led to the Alliance being formed, just so that we had some plan, but we still weren't sure what we would do. Flee, hide, or fight.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sighing, Davis continued. &quot;Ultimately we chose to fight. Not everyone was happy with that decision, or how we came to it, but it's what we chose.&quot;&lt;/div&gt; in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/9815459/10/Future-History&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/9815459/10/Future-History&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Future History, Chapter 10&lt;/a&gt; and the comment in an earlier chapter that some human separatists, lifespan extended to 300 years by nanotech medicine, fled to Andromeda... a trip that's expected to only take 150 years because they'll go much faster once their non-eezo FTL drives clear the hyperspace muck churned up by millennia of eezo FTL use.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; While it would inherently go in a completely different direction than what I'd envisioned, &quot;humans are from another galaxy and arrive before the harvest&quot; can also be entertaining. (A thought inspired by &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/9001395/1/Fifty-Shades-of-Overkill&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/9001395/1/Fifty-Shades-of-Overkill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fifty Shades of Overkill&lt;/a&gt; in which Mass Effect takes place when the future of the Halo-verse starts colonizing another galaxy.)</description>
<category>Mass Effect</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BMiss%20Effect%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 10:31:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Do it over, n00b!</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; How about a &quot;life is a game&quot; story where more than one character is getting a do-over and they can see each others' HUD announcements and the Steam-style achievements cause humorous strife?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;John sighed as he shook his head &quot;Fine...but what should we do now with the others?&quot; Jane sighed as well &quot;Come up with an excuse of course,&quot; She said. &quot;I'll just say I'm your sister or something.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;John nodded, &quot;Sure,&quot; he said, and the two moved out from behind the Crates, however Jane did not see the small grin that was on John's face.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&quot;Ok, now that we've calmed down a bit,&quot; Jane said, &quot;I can explain a bit more. As it turns out, I am John's Sis-&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&quot;She's my Wife.&quot; John interrupted her, &quot;She just pissed that I haven't been home for so long, that's why she pulled a gun on me.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The others just looked at John Gaping, none more so than Jane herself. John just grins at her, and as he walks past her he whispers &quot;No one pulls a gun on Commander John Shepard and gets away with it.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievement Unlocked: Don't F**k with the Shepard (Shepard must put someone back in their place)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/8264615/3/Mass-Effect-Life-is-a-Game&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.fanfiction.net/s/8264615/3/Mass-Effect-Life-is-a-Game&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mass Effect: Life Is A Game, Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<category>But... But... Potential!</category>
<category>FlavorText</category>
<category>Any Series</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BDo%20it%20over%2C%20n00b!%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 02:16:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Untitled Cracky Counter-TCB Idea</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Just an amusing, almost-certainly-cracky way to let humans win in a Conversion Bureau story.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:39:42) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; I've been reading Conversion Bureau parodies and I just thought of an... interesting way for either a Discord-class OC or a sympathetic magic user to counter the uncounterable barrier.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:39:52) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; It involves a crazy scavenger hunt for ingredients to combine and throw at the barrier and the dialogue &quot;It's too bad that Earth doesn't have a thaumic field of its own. Then all we'd have needed for the core of the spell was three toothpicks and 2cc of mouse blood.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:43:59) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; The basic idea is to craft a bundle of reagents that, when combined properly and thrown at the barrier, activate a spell as they're disintegrated for being &quot;man-made&quot; which summons Death and traps in a summoned state inside the barrier until &quot;3. ????? 4. Profit&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:44:58) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; Only way to get rid of him is to shrink the barrier back to nil. If Xenolestia, as people seem to call her, wins, Death is stuck for all time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:45:51) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; In the process, solving the whole &quot;getting something inside the barrier is impossible&quot; problem.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:47:06) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; Of course, the &quot;3. ????? 4. Profit&quot; part of the idea is highly flexible.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(22:47:29) ssokolow:&lt;/strong&gt; The main important detail is to summon the Death of the Discworld in a funny way and, somehow, that winds up saving Humanity from TCB ponies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<category>Subvert That Stupid!</category>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>IdeaFragment</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BUntitled%20Cracky%20Counter-TCB%20Idea%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 04:40:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Ways to Feed a Changeling Hive</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; A collection of ideas for how to feed changelings on various emotions, should your story need it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Lust:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52342/2/forever-a-changeling/chapter-2&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52342/2/forever-a-changeling/chapter-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Run a brothel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Anger:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;  &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/32732/4/outcast-of-a-hivemind/the-prince-and-the-training-montage#comment/811208&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/32732/4/outcast-of-a-hivemind/the-prince-and-the-training-montage#comment/811208&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trolling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Fear:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/32732/7/outcast-of-a-hivemind/brains-before-brawns#comment/846833&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/32732/7/outcast-of-a-hivemind/brains-before-brawns#comment/846833&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Run a haunted house&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<category>Reference</category>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BWays%20to%20Feed%20a%20Changeling%20Hive%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Not So Crazy After All</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; What if there's a pony who hears Changeling telepathy due to a childhood accident but just dismissed it as, at most, mental illness.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I haven't really thought about the details much, but upon reading the quote listed as the source, the idea of &quot;hears changeling telepathy because her neurochemistry was altered by a childhood incident with bad candy&quot; popped to mind.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Obviously, it wouldn't be a continuation of that fic, given the &quot;childhood&quot; part. I'm not locked in on that detail, but it feels like it has more potential.&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; The &quot;childhood&quot; part would allow the character to just be used to the idea that the voices are all in her head.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; It wouldn't automatically rule out Bon Bon for her part in events. Heck, it could make her more vulnerable to Chrysalis's mind control if that'd help the plot.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The &quot;bad candy&quot; part isn't essential... I just get the impression that I don't want something so boringly obvious as &quot;magical mishap&quot; as the cause and &quot;bad candy&quot; imparts a nice touch of silliness to the &quot;origin story&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;I can think of various ways this could be integrated into a story, either as a source of a driving conflict or as something more supplementary. A big determining factor would be where they are during the wedding and how that affects their perspective on the voices in their head.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Source&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;2924612&lt;/code&gt; She continuously ate hallucinogenic candy. For weeks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;From the looks of it, given her semi-realistic changeling experience, it might have altered her neurochemistry enough to make herself compatible with their telepathy and connected her with the hive mind.&lt;br&gt;&lt;span&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; Luminous Lead @ &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/110510/unfamiliar-skin#comment/3345873&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/110510/unfamiliar-skin#comment/3345873&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#3345873&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<category>But... But... Potential!</category>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>IdeaFragment</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BNot%20So%20Crazy%20After%20All%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 21:09:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>GettingStarted</title>
<description>One-time Setup Instructions for editing your downloaded copy of this site.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See Also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#UserGuide&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#UserGuide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;UserGuide&quot;&gt;UserGuide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://tiddlywiki.com/#Browsers&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://tiddlywiki.com/#Browsers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Browser notes on the TiddlyWiki site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;For Firefox Users:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; Before making any other changes, complete the following steps to prevent a flood of security warnings when clicking &quot;save changes&quot;:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Install the &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/tiddlyfox/&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/tiddlyfox/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TiddlyFox&lt;/a&gt; extension to grant &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TiddlyWiki&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TiddlyWiki&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;TiddlyWiki&quot;&gt;TiddlyWiki&lt;/a&gt; permission to save changes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Restart Firefox to complete the installation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The &quot;save changes&quot; and &quot;save empty copy&quot; links in the sidebar and the &quot;save&quot; link in the backstage bar will now behave as expected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt; For Users of Opera and WebKit-based Browsers Like Chrome and Safari:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Install the &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.java.com/en/&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.java.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Java Plugin&lt;/a&gt; in your browser. (You can verify success with Oracle's &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.java.com/en/download/testjava.jsp&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.java.com/en/download/testjava.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Java Test&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Download &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.tiddlywiki.com/TiddlySaver.jar&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.tiddlywiki.com/TiddlySaver.jar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TiddlySaver.jar&lt;/a&gt; and put it in the same folder as this file.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The &quot;save changes&quot; and &quot;save empty copy&quot; links in the sidebar and the &quot;save&quot; link in the backstage bar will now behave as expected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Google Chrome does not currently support Java under MacOS X and Linux and, therefore, editing via Chrome is not supported on those platforms.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt; For Internet Explorer Users:&lt;/h2&gt;See the &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://tiddlywiki.com/#InternetExplorer&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://tiddlywiki.com/#InternetExplorer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TiddlyWiki&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TiddlyWiki&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;TiddlyWiki&quot;&gt;TiddlyWiki&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt; For Everyone:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Enter your username for signing your edits: &lt;input option=&quot;txtUserName&quot; class=&quot;txtOptionInput&quot; title=&quot;Username for signing your edits&quot;&gt; (If you use a cookie whitelisting addon, you'll have to do this &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=430045&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=430045&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;every time&lt;/a&gt; unless you use &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://tiddlywiki.com/#PersistentOptions&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://tiddlywiki.com/#PersistentOptions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;persistent options&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; After making edits, remember to check &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TabMoreMissing&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TabMoreMissing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;TabMoreMissing&quot;&gt;More &amp;gt; Missing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TabMoreOrphans&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TabMoreOrphans&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;TabMoreOrphans&quot;&gt;More &amp;gt; Orphans&lt;/a&gt; in the right sidebar for typos.&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; You can use the search box or &lt;em&gt;more &amp;gt; references&lt;/em&gt; in the tiddler header to find which pages contain links to a given page.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt; For Users of &quot;save empty copy&quot;:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; You'll probably want to edit &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#SiteSubtitle&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#SiteSubtitle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;SiteSubtitle&quot;&gt;SiteSubtitle&lt;/a&gt; (the subtitle of the site, as shown above)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; If you don't add contact instruction to the &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Contact Me&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Contact Me&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Contact Me&quot;&gt;Contact Me&lt;/a&gt; page, please remove the e-mail icon from &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#ActionButtons&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#ActionButtons&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;ActionButtons&quot;&gt;ActionButtons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Before you share this with others, replace &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#GettingStarted&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#GettingStarted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;GettingStarted&quot;&gt;GettingStarted&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Welcome&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Welcome&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#DefaultTiddlers&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#DefaultTiddlers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;DefaultTiddlers&quot;&gt;DefaultTiddlers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Visit &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#BackupOptionsPlugin&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#BackupOptionsPlugin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;BackupOptionsPlugin&quot;&gt;BackupOptionsPlugin&lt;/a&gt; and set &lt;code&gt;%N.backup.html&lt;/code&gt; as the backup filename if you want only one backup version to be preserved. (Again, if you use CS Lite...)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Repeatedly generate a &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:;&quot; title=&quot;Generate a random colour scheme for your TiddlyWiki&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;New ColorPalette&lt;/a&gt; until satisfied and then &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:;&quot; title=&quot;Save all tiddlers to create a new TiddlyWiki&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; accesskey=&quot;S&quot;&gt;save changes&lt;/a&gt;. (Edit &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#ColorPalette&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#ColorPalette&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;ColorPalette&quot;&gt;ColorPalette&lt;/a&gt; to manually adjust generated color schemes. Delete it to reset to the default &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TiddlyWiki&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#TiddlyWiki&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;TiddlyWiki&quot;&gt;TiddlyWiki&lt;/a&gt; color scheme.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<category>includeNew</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#GettingStarted</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 21:08:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Given A Bad Name</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; What if Queen Chrysalis is one of many changeling queens but her huge swarm of drones is something other queens abandoned long ago in favor of a more sustainable feeding strategy?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When I read &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/121586/3/the-golden-daughter/3-the-hardest-lesson&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/121586/3/the-golden-daughter/3-the-hardest-lesson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Golden Daughter, Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;, the fact that drones only normally live for a few weeks and never more than three months struck me as something none of my other ideas would be compatible with.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I started to ponder on how one might write a &quot;Changelings and Ponies living together in harmony&quot; story with such a restriction ruling out the more typical solutions and here's what I got:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Without even having read to the end where it's shown that the author and I were thinking in similar directions, The Golden Daughter already gave me the impression that it may be feasible for a changeling queen to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; birth a hive and to have many daughters, more like ponies, if their culture and their food supply weren't precluding it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Therefore, why not have it that Chrysalis is a cultural throwback. A queen who adopted an ill-advised hive-building strategy abandoned ages ago and is too foolish or egotistical to change?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In turn, there could be *many* queens who, instead, seek out same-sex pairings and, once they've built up sufficient trust and an understanding of their partner, carefully reveal their true nature. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This would have several beneficial characteristics for mares who accept them:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; They'd have the option of having daughters without needing to involve a stallion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; With sufficient preparation to dig a hive beneath their house, they could have drones taking up roles similar to Harry Potter house elves.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; They'd have a spouse who has an incentive to remain faithful and keep the relationship strong.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; They'd have a spouse who can shapeshift, be it for bedroom fun, fashion experimentation, pranks, or any other conceivable use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Given how many changeling ideas I already have, it'd probably be a good idea to try to shift my focus elsewhere for a bit to accumulate some others but I'll also need to work on how to distance this from the other two. So far, the main distinctions I can see are:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;twtable&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;evenRow&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Adopted Family, Changing Times&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Adopted Family, Changing Times&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Adopted Family, Changing Times&quot;&gt;Adopted Family, Changing Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;This&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;oddRow&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Takes place in Canterlot&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Takes place somewhere distant from Canterlot (and not Ponyville)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;evenRow&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Features a drone who stays in touch with the hive&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Features one of many queens who live more like ponies than classical changelings&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;oddRow&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;The plot is touched off when Chrysalis ruins the happy lives of changelings like our protagonist fairly directly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;The plot is touched off when our lead reads about the invasion in the paper and feels pressured to tell her lover before she feels confident rather than risking getting caught without a chance to explain.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;evenRow&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Resolving the driving conflict will probably have significance for Pony-Changeling relations in general&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Resolving the driving conflict has no bigger implications. It's just a story about two lovers in a town the main cast has no interest in.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;I didn't bother to chart &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Unorthodox Metamorphosis&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Unorthodox Metamorphosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Unorthodox Metamorphosis&quot;&gt;Unorthodox Metamorphosis&lt;/a&gt; because, aside from probably focusing on an ensemble cast and having more emphasis on &quot;in the large&quot; elements, it's basically the same as &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink null&quot; href=&quot;http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Adopted Family, Changing Times&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#Adopted Family, Changing Times&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; refresh=&quot;link&quot; tiddlylink=&quot;Adopted Family, Changing Times&quot;&gt;Adopted Family, Changing Times&lt;/a&gt; in how it differs from this story.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Also, having now finished reading The Golden Daughter, I should also mention that I wouldn't have drones as merely the result of malnourished pupae. That's a little too &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_new_world&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_new_world&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brave New World&lt;/a&gt;&quot; for my tastes. Instead, I'd probably have them as just another template stored in a changeling queen's DNA and selectable at the time of conception. Instead of &quot;mayfly sapients&quot;, their mentality could be more like trained dogs which use a hive-link to obey orders by automatically drawing any requisite knowledge from their queen's head.)</description>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BGiven%20A%20Bad%20Name%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 14:38:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Unorthodox Metamorphosis</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; What if there were a hive of changelings whose queen died off long ago and who ended up surviving in a sustainable state of &quot;slowly dying off&quot; by converting ponies to reproduce?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Origin&lt;/h1&gt;While reading &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52342/forever-a-changeling&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52342/forever-a-changeling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Forever a Changeling&lt;/a&gt;, the following facts were revealed in roughly this order:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Rainbow dash is a changeling who didn't know she was a changeling until she was hit by a revealing spell.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; There are multiple hives in Equestria and Chrysalis is not well-liked for brining negative attention to the species.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; When a hive loses its queen, that's it. Without any means to reproduce, the drones eventually die off and the hive ceases to be.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; There exists at least one other pony who is from the same hive and doesn't know she's a Changeling.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;Given that the mechanism by which this situation was accomplished was revealed very late in the story compared to those other details, I started wondering if, maybe, there existed a hive that, having lost their queen, had turned to some kind of conversion spell (or other technique) to &quot;reproduce&quot; rather than simply accepting the inevitable and, as a side-effect, had become very decentralized compared to other hives.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;My guess was wrong but I think it has enough merit as an idea for it to deserve being made into part of a fic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Acquiring Ponies to Convert&lt;/h1&gt;I haven't put much work into nailing this down yet because it'll be central to the character of the changelings and the tone of the story and I'm not yet sure which ones would make the story the most interesting. As such, this is more a collection of notes on the implications of various decisions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;First, let's assume they only convert ponies who won't be missed and are either willing or infants for two simple reasons:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Converting a subject who is unwilling or will be missed is foolish because, sooner or later, they'll be brought to the attention of the authorities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; If their goal is to preserve their group identity, they need to convert subjects who are willing to take on that identity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Despite leaving so much up in the air, I already know that brainwashing or any other kind of mental modification runs counter to the tone I want (though I'm not yet ruling out the possibility that it was tried at some point in the past. It will require more thought.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first question is what types of ponies they look for:&lt;br&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Infants&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt; Makes for the most stability, since the new drones will never remember &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; being drones, but, in a setting like Equestria, it doesn't feel very plausible to be able to find that many unwanted babies and it also doesn't make for a very interesting story since their switch to a new method of &quot;reproduction&quot; has no significant challenges to overcome once they decide on it.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Foals&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt; Let's assume that orphanages exist in significant number and there are enough orphans to populate them. (As various Scootaloo-orphan fics have shown, this is plausible. If Ponyville can have an orphanage, then what must bigger population centres be like?) This is probably the most interesting single slice of the population to use. To keep their secret, they'd have to gain a possibly jaded child's trust and, at the same time, trust the child to keep first their adopted parents nature secret and, later, their own new nature too. However, at the same time, successfully converting foals is probably the most viable mixture of &quot;young enough to raise in the culture&quot; and &quot;numerous enough to prevent the population from shrinking&quot;.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;dt&gt; Seriously/Fatally Injured Adults&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt; Unlike in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52342/forever-a-changeling&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52342/forever-a-changeling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Forever a Changeling&lt;/a&gt;, this isn't really a viable option for a normal modus operandi. The subject is effectively under duress when making their decision and has no reason to want to integrate into the culture in question.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;dd&gt; &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, this could still be used to make the story more interesting if, while uncommon (and possibly frowned upon), there do exist otherwise ordinary ponies who are in on the secret and happen to be in changeling bodies because they were close friends with a changeling who used some aspect of the conversion process to save their lives.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;dt&gt; Socially Isolated Adults&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt; While it's difficult to believably make this a significant source of converts, given that Equestria is supposed to be the land of friendship, and ineffective at producing a progression of generations unless the adults are young adults, this is actually a surprisingly plausible way to gain converts who fervently preserve and pass on their culture.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;dd&gt; It's the same technique both religious congregations and cults use: Find someone in need of a social group, welcome them with open arms, and increase their expected adherence to the group norm gradually. Done properly, even if they ever decide they do want out, they won't risk alienating their entire social network.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;dd&gt; In this case, it would work even better than relgions and cults as long as they avoid the risk of disillusionment with the whole &quot;hide what we are and feed on emotions&quot; part, work carefully to prevent converts from abusing their disguise abilities, and look for the extreme cases who are already willing to give their undying loyalty to anyone who can deliver on a promise that they'll never be alone again. (eg. Trixie in &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/26961/mirrors-image&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/26961/mirrors-image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mirror's Image&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Name&lt;/h1&gt;Unorthodox Metamorphosis probably wouldn't be the final name for this idea. Even if the story's focus does turn out to be appropriate, I'm still looking for a less bland word than unorthodox.</description>
<category>But... But... Potential!</category>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BUnorthodox%20Metamorphosis%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 12:51:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Adopted Family, Changing Times</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; How about a story where it's common for MLP Changelings to be raised by pony families and then, when Chrysalis's invasion fails, focus is put on one of the changelings who now resents Chrysalis for what they see as Chrysalis getting greedy and destroying countless changelings' lives on a stupid gamble.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So far, every story I've seen breaks from the idea in one of the following ways:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Replacement is a temporary thing done when the true bearer of the identity is out of town, more like succubi and incubi than classical changelings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; A stillborn foal &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; replaced, but it's an exceptional situation and the foal may not grow up knowing what they really are. (eg. &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/26961/mirrors-image&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/26961/mirrors-image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mirror's Image&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; There's no replacement. The ponies know that the kid is a changeling (even if they don't really know what a changeling is) but the kid has no contact with &quot;their changeling relatives&quot; until the masquerade is broken. (eg. &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/78117/the-irony-of-applejack&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/78117/the-irony-of-applejack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Irony of Applejack&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/23224/smoke-and-mirrors&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/23224/smoke-and-mirrors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Smoke and Mirrors&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; the changelings craft identities from scratch once they've already reached a sufficient level of maturity (eg. &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/22618/flitter&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/22618/flitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/87718/a-novel-tale&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/87718/a-novel-tale&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Novel Tale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/22178/love-mine&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/22178/love-mine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Love Mine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52953/without-a-hive&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/52953/without-a-hive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Without a Hive&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) rather than growing up with a loving pony family.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;The idea came to me while I was reading &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/124014/1/deception-is-magic/arrival&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/124014/1/deception-is-magic/arrival&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Deception is Magic, Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt; (before it was confirmed that this Twilight was a changeling queen) when I started wondering how one might go about making a changeling Twilight Sparkle canonically-minded enough to sing &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0VbyYcljx8&quot; title=&quot;External link to https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u0VbyYcljx8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BBBFF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, of course, since she &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a queen in Deception is Magic, she's not exactly a representative example, but these dialogue snippets (intentionally leaving out who's speaking or what their emotional state is) should help to convey what I was imagining for a more ordinary changeling character with a similarly strong connection to their pony family whose world was overturned by a canonically-behaving Chrysalis:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;It's standard changeling practice. We watch the hospitals for stillbirths, erase their memory of that specific detail, and leave behind an infant with some basic, instinctive knowledge. The hive gets a source of food, the foal gets two loving families and all the food they could ever need, and the parents don't have to mourn a foal who never was. Everyone's happy... until a certain someone got greedy and decided to pluck the golden goose.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Please don't make me choose between my birth and adopted families. I don't think I could live with myself unless Queen Chrysalis knows a memory spell strong enough to build me a whole new past... and I think death would be kinder than leaving a stranger to walk around with my face.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
<category>In A Different Light</category>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<category>FlavorText</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BAdopted%20Family%2C%20Changing%20Times%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 01:53:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>Alicorn Pinkie Pie</title>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine if, either instead of or in addition to Twilight Sparkle, Pinkie Pie became an alicorn somehow.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let's think divergently for a moment and assume that what season 3 canon says about becoming an alicorn is merely a suggestion. (As any fic written prior to season 3 automatically succeeds at.) How much fun could be had were Pinkie Pie to become an alicorn? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; It could be a comedy. Even if she doesn't cause chaos herself, everyone else can cause chaos by reacting to the idea of her having magic, her being de facto royalty, or whatever other delightful thing you can think of to get people worrying about or misinterpreting the implications of. (Can you imagine adding the ability to fly and do magic to our 4th-wall-breaking, prank-loving party animal? The implications alone could cause panic.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; It could be serious. It'd be tricky, but there's definitely plenty of room to interpret.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/57026/17/ascend/ascension&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/57026/17/ascend/ascension&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ascend, Chapter 17&lt;/a&gt; by xTSGx&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; It'd probably share characteristics with &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/122018/td-the-alicorn-princess&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/122018/td-the-alicorn-princess&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TD the Alicorn Princess&lt;/a&gt; by BronyWriter (if for no other reason than because TD is going to cause a lot of fun chaos as &quot;the princess of snark and sarcasm&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/105303/4/pandelirium/chapter-7-no-such-thing&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/105303/4/pandelirium/chapter-7-no-such-thing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pandelirium&lt;/a&gt; has such a thing, but it's overshadowed by other things. (Pinkie is already an imaginary friend given physical form and, as such, she has shapeshifting powers she generally avoids using and gained her alicorn status in a manner that didn't give her enough pegasus-ness and unicorn-ness to grant her default form wings and a horn.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;externalLink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fimfiction.net/story/92077/the-great-alicorn-hunt/&quot; title=&quot;External link to http://www.fimfiction.net/story/92077/the-great-alicorn-hunt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Great Alicorn Hunt&lt;/a&gt; does it, but it also does it for the rest of the mane six and plays it more seriously than I'd intended.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<category>MLP:FiM</category>
<category>But... But... Potential!</category>
<category>PlotWhim</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#%5B%5BAlicorn%20Pinkie%20Pie%5D%5D</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 16:58:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
<item>
<title>MLP:FiM</title>
<description>Ideas using My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic as a source.</description>
<category>SourceSeries</category>
<link>http://ssokolow.com/story_ideas.html#MLP%3AFiM</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 02:03:00 GMT</pubDate>

</item>
</channel>
</rss>
